<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Krishna&#39;s Webplace</title>
	<link>https://krishnayadav.xyz/blog/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Blogs on Krishna&#39;s Webplace</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en-us</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 21:05:20 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://krishnayadav.xyz/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	
	
	<item>
		<title>Sign a Custom ROM Build</title>
		<link>https://krishnayadav.xyz/blog/sign-a-custom-rom-build/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 21:05:20 +0530</pubDate>
		
		<guid>https://krishnayadav.xyz/blog/sign-a-custom-rom-build/</guid>
		<description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;this-guide-will-explain-how-to-sign-a-custom-rom-build-typically-unofficial-builds-as-most-official-roms-are-now-shipping-their-own-private-keys&#34;&gt;This guide will explain how to &lt;strong&gt;sign&lt;/strong&gt; a Custom ROM build (typically unofficial builds, as most official ROMs are now shipping their own private keys).&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.lineageos.org/signing_builds&#34;&gt;Lineage wiki guide&lt;/a&gt;, but simplify it in my own words at places where I feel this guide did not give more practical information to a new comer like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The steps to &lt;strong&gt;Generate the keys&lt;/strong&gt; are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: You only need to run this once. If you ever rerun these, you’ll need to migrate between builds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to the directory where all yours rom files are originally synced (the root of your custom rom files). Now open a terminal and issue this command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: Please note this beforehand that running the following code will ask you to enter password for several keys and several number of times. I will say that just enter 1 password and copy+paste it on all the places where it asks for a password to be entered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_do-note-this-password-down-as-we-will-have-to-use-it-when-we-sign-the-builds_&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;DO NOTE THIS PASSWORD DOWN, as we will have to use it when we sign the builds.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;subject&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;/C=US/ST=California/L=Mountain View/O=Android/OU=Android/CN=Android/emailAddress=android@android.com&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;
mkdir ~/.android-certs
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; cert in bluetooth cyngn-app media networkstack platform releasekey sdk_sandbox shared testcert testkey verity; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;    ./development/tools/make_key ~/.android-certs/$cert &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;$subject&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;\
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we need are required to re-sign APEX keys. To do so, simply run the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;cp ./development/tools/make_key ~/.android-certs/
sed -i &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;s|2048|4096|g&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt; ~/.android-certs/make_key
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now finally, we must generate our keys. I will strongly recommend you to generate them &lt;strong&gt;with&lt;/strong&gt; a password (re-use the password you used in step 1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The command to run is in &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.lineageos.org/signing_builds#generate-keys-with-a-password&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: If you have issues following up with these steps, I have a script that will execute the commands for you (of course, you have to manually enter the password for each keys). You can find that script &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ObsidianMaximus/scripts/blob/master/signing/Generate_Keys.sh&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usage (copy paste this in terminal):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;curl -O https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ObsidianMaximus/scripts/master/signing/Generate_Keys.sh
bash Generate_Keys.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the steps to &lt;strong&gt;make a .zip flashable package&lt;/strong&gt; are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source the envsetup.sh by executing this command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;source build/envsetup.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now finally, we will have to start compiling the files for our custom ROM (this will take a long time, depending on your computer&amp;rsquo;s specs). To do so, run the following command (replacing the codename with your device codename):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;breakfast &amp;lt;codename&amp;gt;
mka target-files-package otatools
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, it is time to sign all of our APKs and APEXes and build the .zip package. To do so, you need to execute some commands, which I have bundled in a script as they are too long to be inserted here. To execute the script, do as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NOTE&lt;/strong&gt;: When you run this script, it will ask you your password that you had set earlier. Expect to enter that several number of times here as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;curl -O https://raw.githubusercontent.com/ObsidianMaximus/scripts/master/signing/Sign.sh
bash Sign.sh
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations, you have successfully signed the build. Now in case you are wondering where the .zip file is (no, it is not in the usual out directory), the .zip is right in the android root tree, where you issued the commands from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just clean flash the &lt;strong&gt;signed-ota_update.zip&lt;/strong&gt; and device integrity should be met now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Ubuntu Server Setup Part 1</title>
		<link>https://krishnayadav.xyz/blog/ubuntu-server-setup-part-1/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 19:46:03 +0530</pubDate>
		
		<guid>https://krishnayadav.xyz/blog/ubuntu-server-setup-part-1/</guid>
		<description>&lt;p&gt;I was wanting to learn on how to setup my servers and host stuff on them, but to host a server online, one needs to spend some amount of money on them, which i really didn&amp;rsquo;t want to. But then i remembered that i have one old dusty home computer that had been lying in my home since several years, while not really being used anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So i decided to use this opportunity to reuse the same computer for my server tasks and in this way, i will be saving up on those server costs that i would have to pay [electricity is cheap here].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But i had a hurdle in my path, and that was my old monitor not working, due to which i was unable to get my cpu to give a basic display as it had only VGA output. And well, i couldn&amp;rsquo;t really use this PC with my current monitor, as this monitor supports only HDMI and Display Port. I did have one VGA-to-HDMI converter lying around with me, but that had malfunctioned as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This had me worried for some time before i thought of just using the gpu in my current setup on the older one. Sadly, this had another issue. The older desktop is an Intel Pentium E5400, and has a motherboard which is of LGA775 socket type. Now, this motherboard has the onboard power supply cables right above the PCIe slot, which rendered me placing my hefty gpu in that slot useless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then i had to think a bit more and got an idea of just taking out the HDD from the old PC and placing it in my working desktop [silly me]. I attached the HDD to my newer PC and started the machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, i went for the trusted server OS, Debian. Flashed it onto my usb drive and tried live booting only to be suprised with no display. Forgot that i had to enable CSM from BIOS and then turn on &amp;ldquo;legacy only&amp;rdquo; mode to allow the usb to boot [had partitioned it as MSDOS/MBR, silly me, again..]. This was again because the older computer had legacy BIOS only and i had to test the current HDD to ensure that it did boot alright under legacy conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adjusted boot options and booted the PC only to be met by a weirdly enlarged debian graphical installer. Pressed enter and the PC restarted and i was met with just blurred out lines and teared display with the text not legible at all. Tried rebooting several times from my usb drive but was met with the same issue again and again. Finally got quite frustrated and flashed ubuntu server on the drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Booted from it and to my surprise, it turned on smoothly. At first the screen was enlarged but when i progressed the installation, it auto-adjusted normally and matched my 24&amp;quot; screen resolution quite well. Installed the ubuntu server, which was pretty straight forward, thanks to the KIS ways of Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then my next task was getting my wifi modem or should i say TP-Link USB Network Adapter (Archer T2U Plus) in working condition, as i planned to keep the pc in an isolated place. &lt;strong&gt;The instructions for the same can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ObsidianMaximus/wifidrivers/blob/master/commands_for_drivers.sh&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; This adapter uses a Realtek &lt;strong&gt;RTL8821AU Chipset&lt;/strong&gt; at its heart, which fortunately has linux drivers available, thanks to aircrack-ng!
Executing the commands in the script installed all it&amp;rsquo;s drivers. Now next, i had to enable it and connect to my home network to make the pc accessible by my other devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this, here is an excellent guide from &lt;a href=&#34;https://ubuntu.com/core/docs/networkmanager/configure-wifi-connections&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the steps i followed, they were as follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Firstly, i had to install &lt;strong&gt;network-manager&lt;/strong&gt; as it was not present by default on the default server installation [ strange? ].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next, i ran &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;nmcli d&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; command to get the name of the wifi device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then, to turn it on, issue: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;nmcli r wifi on&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and list all the scanned wifi networks with: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;nmcli d wifi list&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To connect to one of the networks listed, you have to type: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;nmcli d wifi connect &amp;lt;name of the wifi&amp;gt; password &amp;lt;password for that wifi&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;  [Replace stuff within &amp;lt; &amp;gt; with what you have got listed in the above step.]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It took several seconds but after that it did get connected to my wifi network! I restarted my pc without the ethernet cable and the wifi did indeed work, although on startup, one of the checks done by systemd made me wait for quite a long time, more on that &lt;a href=&#34;https://askubuntu.com/questions/972215/a-start-job-is-running-for-wait-for-network-to-be-configured-ubuntu-server-17-1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then took out the HDD and inserted it into my older desktop and sadly, even after it being turned on for several minutes, i had no green led light show up on the wifi usb adapter [which is used to indicate that the modem is in use by the OS], thus, the older pc was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; turning on properly and i had no way to get to diagnosing the issue as i just didn&amp;rsquo;t have a display [running it headless].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that i will have to indeed get my monitor repaired to continue on with my experimentations on my newly built home server.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Use SSH or Rsync With Android</title>
		<link>https://krishnayadav.xyz/blog/use-ssh-or-rsync-with-android/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2024 09:28:58 +0530</pubDate>
		
		<guid>https://krishnayadav.xyz/blog/use-ssh-or-rsync-with-android/</guid>
		<description>&lt;p&gt;Today, i wanted to send a file from my desktop to my android device. I thought of using rsync for this purpose, which is a tool that i use frequently to sync files between my desktop and my laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought of giving it a try and came across &lt;a href=&#34;https://howtos.davidsebek.com/android-rsync-termux.html&#34;&gt;this great article&lt;/a&gt; that explained just this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;note-this-guide-requires-both-the-computer-and-the-android-device-to-be-on-the-same-wifi-network&#34;&gt;NOTE: This guide requires both the computer and the Android device to be on the same wifi network.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process to send files from PC to Android which i took was as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Install rsync on termux using the command: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt install rsync&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and install openssh using the command: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt install openssh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then setup the internal storage of our Android device to be accessible by termux using the command: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;termux-setup-storage&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Grant termux the permission to access storage when prompted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now, change the sshd config file to allow termux to use SSH port. Termux does not have the permission to use the default SSH port 22, so we will use 8022 port instead. For doing this, edit the ../usr/etc/ssh/sshd_config file by simply using the command: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;echo &amp;quot;Port 8022&amp;quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ../usr/etc/ssh/sshd_config&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s get the local ip address of our device by using the command: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;ifconfig&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The ip address should be usually in the end and will be after &amp;ldquo;inet&amp;rdquo; . Or you can just go to Settings app and click on wifi and select the wifi you are connected to and look for the ipv4 address. In either of these 2 cases, the ip address should usually begin with &lt;strong&gt;192.168.xx.xx&lt;/strong&gt; where x&amp;rsquo;s are to be replaced by your ip address part.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup a password for the user by using the command: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;passwd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, we have to start the SSH daemon. To do this, enter this in termux: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;sshd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-using-ssh-&#34;&gt;For using SSH :&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open terminal on your pc and type: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh -p 8022 192.168.xx.xx&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; [where the x&amp;rsquo;s are replaced by your ipv4 address part].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You should now be able to use android terminal through your desktop terminal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-using-rsync-&#34;&gt;For using Rsync :&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply enter the command : &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;rsync -e &#39;ssh -p 8022&#39; &amp;lt;file to transfer from pc&amp;gt; 192.168.xx.xx:/data/data/com.termux/files/home/storage/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explanation of some stuff in the above commands :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The -e command is used to specify the remote shell to use. For more details, check the manpage of rsync.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The x&amp;rsquo;s replace your ipv4 address parts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;/data/data/com.termux/files/home/storage/&lt;/strong&gt; is the &amp;ldquo;usual&amp;rdquo; path of the main storage in our Android which the user can access, so we are sending the file from our desktop to our Android device&amp;rsquo;s internal storage using this. You can specify some folder to send the file into directly by simply adding the folder after &lt;strong&gt;storage/&lt;/strong&gt; in the command. If this shows an error message when you try to transfer files, just type: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;pwd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in termux to get your current directory where you wish to send/receive the files and replace output of this command with the path in the step 1 command above after your phone&amp;rsquo;s ip address.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This should work in vice-versa as well. Just add the path to copy from Android first and the path to copy to in your desktop after this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;side-note&#34;&gt;Side Note:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To avoid entering password all the time while accessing SSH/Rsync, generate a key pair on your pc using the command: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh-keygen&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and then copy it to Android using the command: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh-copy-id -p 8022 192.168.xx.xx&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; in your desktop terminal. This will ask you password only once and after authenticating it, you can now just use SSH/Rsync without entering that password which we generated in the &amp;ldquo;Step 5&amp;rdquo; in the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REMEMBER&lt;/strong&gt; that the ip address of your android device can change from time to time due to ip addresses being dynamic when using wifi. Or they &amp;ldquo;may&amp;rdquo; change if the router is restarted. In any case, be sure to repeat the &amp;ldquo;Step 4&amp;rdquo; which we did in the beginning to find our local ip address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Ubuntu Touch Port Part 1</title>
		<link>https://krishnayadav.xyz/blog/ubuntutouchportpart1/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 13:38:00 +0530</pubDate>
		
		<guid>https://krishnayadav.xyz/blog/ubuntutouchportpart1/</guid>
		<description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I recently decided to get more involved in the Android world and came about a &amp;lsquo;new&amp;rsquo; type of OS, known as Ubuntu Touch. I thought a bit on it and decided to start the porting process for it for my device Realme GT Neo 2 [codenamed:bitra].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.ubports.com/en/latest/porting/introduction/index.html&#34;&gt;official documentation of UBports&lt;/a&gt; where in they gave some good amount of introduction on how and why certain things needed to be done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guide mentions the use of GSI for devices with Android 8+ and, as my device is indeed treble supported, I think I will head to using GSI only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.ubports.com/en/latest/porting/build_and_boot/standalone_kernel_build.html&#34;&gt;Standalone Kernel Method (Halium 9 and newer)&lt;/a&gt; is very interesting as it seems to be the least tiresome way for porting among all of the 3 mentioned methods. So I started with this and did the steps as mentioned in the guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The defconfig that i had to use is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/Krishna-Yadav/android_kernel_realme_sm8250/-/blob/master/arch/arm64/configs/vendor/sm8250_defconfig?ref_type=heads&#34;&gt;sm8250_defconfig&lt;/a&gt;. Next i made a halium.config file as prompted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, i had to fill in the deviceinfo file. For this purpose, I used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/ubports/porting/community-ports/android11/xiaomi-poco-x3-pro/xiaomi-vayu&#34;&gt;Poco X3 Pro device branch&lt;/a&gt; as a dummy template and started filling stuff according to it and the guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I got stuck on the &lt;em&gt;deviceinfo_bootimg_prebuilt_dtb&lt;/em&gt; step as i was not sure where to find my dtb. So i asked this question in the telegram group of Ubports and was recommended to run a script on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://krishnayadav.xyz/bootimageextractionguide/index.html&#34;&gt;boot.img which i had extracted&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The script was by LOS. It can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LineageOS/android_system_tools_mkbootimg/lineage-18.1/unpack_bootimg.py&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; [use it through curl -O options]. And it worked! I was able to get the output from my boot.img using the script by running this command : &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;python unpack_bootimg.py --boot_img boot.img&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-scripts-output-in-normal-format&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The script&amp;rsquo;s output in normal format.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://krishnayadav.xyz/img/pyScriptLOS18.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, i was recommended to add the option &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;--format mkbootimg&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; along with the above command to get the outputed text in terms of mkbootimg arguments, as it would output the values that were expected for the &lt;strong&gt;deviceinfo&lt;/strong&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately for me though, adding that option to the command gave me an error : &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;error: unrecognized arguments: --format mkbootimg&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then thought and checked the latest LOS branch from where i had got that previous script. And i did find an updated script from LOS21 that did have those options that i needed for mkbootimg format. The new script can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LineageOS/android_system_tools_mkbootimg/lineage-21.0/unpack_bootimg.py&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this, i ran the command again, now with the additional parameters to it and was indeed able to generate the output in mkbootimg format without any errors! The updated command : &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;python unpack_bootimg.py --boot_img boot.img --format mkbootimg&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-scripts-output-in-mkbootimg-format&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The script&amp;rsquo;s output in mkbootimg format.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://krishnayadav.xyz/img/pyScriptLOS21.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has given me alot to work with now. I will be looking forward to progress even further and complete the deviceinfo file.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Boot Image Extraction Guide</title>
		<link>https://krishnayadav.xyz/blog/bootimageextractionguide/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 21:53:31 +0530</pubDate>
		
		<guid>https://krishnayadav.xyz/blog/bootimageextractionguide/</guid>
		<description>&lt;p&gt;Guide on how to extract a boot image from any Android phone [Requires Magisk and Computer]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting started!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accessing and modifying system files on your device typically requires superuser permissions. To extract the boot image, we&amp;rsquo;ll need a root environment. We&amp;rsquo;ll achieve this by using Magisk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;manual-process&#34;&gt;Manual Process&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, make sure you install TWRP and then flash Magisk through it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setup Magisk in your phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connect your phone to your Computer and type adb shell [Ensure that you have adb setup properly].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now, become root by typing &lt;strong&gt;su&lt;/strong&gt; in the shell on your PC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy/Paste the following code in the shell.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; PARTITION in &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;boot&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;boot_a&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;boot_b&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
  BLOCK&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;find /dev/block &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;\(&lt;/span&gt; -type b -o -type c -o -type l &lt;span style=&#34;color:#ae81ff&#34;&gt;\)&lt;/span&gt; -iname &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;$PARTITION&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; -print -quit 2&amp;gt;/dev/null&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt; -n &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;$BLOCK&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
    echo &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;$PARTITION&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;readlink -f &lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;$BLOCK&lt;span style=&#34;color:#e6db74&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;fi&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This command will display the boot partition paths for both A/B and A-only devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;note&#34;&gt;Note!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&#34;https://source.android.com/docs/core/ota/ab&#34;&gt;A/B devices&lt;/a&gt;, the loop command will display the boot partition paths for both slots, something like this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;boot_a &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; /dev/block/sda40
boot_b &lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; /dev/block/sda41
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this case, you can extract the image corresponding to your currently active slot.To determine the active slot, enter the command &lt;code&gt;getprop ro.boot.slot_suffix&lt;/code&gt;. If the output is _a, use the path for boot_a; otherwise, use the path for boot_b.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, use the following command to extract the image from the specified boot path:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;dd &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt;boot_partition_path&amp;gt; of&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&amp;lt;output_path&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;dd &lt;span style=&#34;color:#66d9ef&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;/dev/block/mmcblk0p42 of&lt;span style=&#34;color:#f92672&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;/sdcard/boot_a.img
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope this did work for you, as it did indeed work for me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CREDITS : &lt;a href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/gitclone-url/a1f693b64d8f8701ec24477a2ccaab87&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Donate</title>
		<link>https://krishnayadav.xyz/donate/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>https://krishnayadav.xyz/donate/</guid>
		<description>&lt;p&gt;If you do like my work, you can donate me here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://paypal.me/krishnayadavxyz&#34;&gt;PayPal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monero: 46Es9cwspxoY9hhYMy2mdGLwxpYouLWANaBVWiUhhjE37Mr1bB65cU4C9cLkCiaw3hWVaZij7xZs4DrPVUFxTPy5CCkVvsr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monero QR:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://krishnayadav.xyz/Monero.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPI: obsidianmaximus@paytm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;QR code for UPI:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://krishnayadav.xyz/paytm.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	</channel>
</rss>
